This is the solutions video for classifying images.
本视频将讲解图像分类部分的解决方案
First we need to define the classify images function.
首先 定义函数 classify_images
The doc string indicates we will have the following input parameters: image_ dir,
这里的文档字符串指出 我们会有以下输入参数：
the folder with the pet images,
image_ dir 该参数指向存有宠物图像的文件夹
petlabel_dic, the dictionary we created in get pet labels function where the keys are
Petlabel_dic 即我们在函数 get_pet_labels 中创建的字典
the file names of the images and the values are the pet image labels themselves.
该字典以图像文件名为键 以宠物图像标签为值
Model, the CNN model architecture you'll be using to classify the images.
model 即你用来分类图像的 CNN 模型结构
This takes a value of either resnet,
可设为 resnet、alexnet 或 vgg 的任一个值
alexnet, or vgg, all in lowercase letters.
输入值时需全小写
This function returns the dictionary results_dic,
函数会返回字典 results_dic
where the key is the image file name and the value is a list.
该字典以图像文件名为键 以列表为值
In this list, index zero has the pet image label,
在字典列表中 索引 0 为宠物图像标签
index one has a classifier label,
索引 1 为分类器标签
and index two indicates whether or not
索引 2 则会指出
the classifier label and the pet image label match.
分类器标签和宠物图像标签是否匹配
In this function we'll create an empty dictionary,
在函数中 我们要创建一个空字典 results_dic
results_dic, which will be returned at the end of the function.
该字典会在函数末尾返回出来
Next, we'll use a for loop to iterate through
接着 用 for 循环对字典 petlabel_dic 进行迭代
the petlabel_dic dictionary processing each pet image stored in the dictionary.
遍历字典中的所有宠物图像
In this for loop, we'll use
在 for 循环里
the pet image filename when we
用分类器函数 classifier 分类各宠物图像时
classify each of the pet images with the classifier function.
我们需要用到宠物图像文件名
We'll format the label returned by this function and we'll determine
我们会对分类器函数返回出来的标签进行格式化
whether or not the pet label and the classifier labels match.
还要确定宠物标签和分类器标签是否匹配
At the end of the for loop,
在循环末尾
we'll add the labels and whether or not the labels
将每个文件名的标签与标签匹配结果
match to the results_dic dictionary for each file name.
添加到字典 results_dic 中
The first thing we're going to do in the for loop,
在 for 循环中 首先
is we're going to use the classifier function to create those classifier labels.
用函数 classifier 创建分类器标签
They'll be returned as the model label into our classifier function we pass the model,
函数会将结果作为 model_label 返回出来 在函数 classifier 中 我们要输入模型
and then that fullpath to the pet image.
和 pet_images 文件夹的全路径
The key is the filename,
这里的键为文件名
and the image_dir is going to be that pet images folder.
image_dir 指的是那个 pet_images 文件夹
To process those classifier labels,
接着处理这些分类器标签
we use the lower function to put all the letters in lowercase,
用函数 lower 将所有字母设为小写字母
and we use the strip function to strip off leading and trailing white space.
用函数 strip 来删除前后的空格
Remember our petlabel_dic has the value of
记住 petlabel_dic 的值
the pet image label so truth becomes that pet image label.
是宠物图像标签 我们将其赋给 truth
Here we're using the find function to see if we can
这一行用函数 find 来检查
find that pet image label within the classifier label.
分类器标签里是否有 truth 所指的宠物图像标签
If found is greater than zero,
如果函数 found 的值大于 0
this means that we found the pet label within the classifier label.
那就意味着我们在分类器标签里找到了宠物标签
To handle cases where the pet label is a short word like cat or
有时候 宠物标签是短单词 比如 cat 或 fox
fox that can be embedded within the term foxhound or polecat,
这些词可能嵌在 foxhound (猎狐犬) 或 polecat (臭鼬) 里 要处理这种问题
we use the second conditional statement.
我们就得用另一个条件语句
The second conditional statement checks that
这个条件语句检查
the pet label starts at the beginning of the classifier label or,
宠物标签的第一个字母是否也是分类器标签的第一个字母
has a blank in front of it.
也就是宠物标签前是否有空格
Additionally, it checks that the pet label ends at the end of
此外 该语句还会检查宠物标签的最后一个字母是否也是分类器标签的最后一个字母
the classifier label or enter the blank or comma.
也就是宠物标签后是否有空格或逗号
Once it's passed both conditional statements,
一旦这两个条件同时为真
we added to results_dic with comparison set to one.
我们就把比较值设为 1 并添加到字典 results_dic 中
If it didn't pass a conditional statements,
如果有一个条件为假
it's add to result_dic with a comparison set to zero.
那就将比较值设为 0 并添加到 results_dic 中
Finally, we return the result_dic dictionary at the end of the function.
最后 在函数末尾返回字典 results_dic
This is the call to the classifier images function within the main function.
这里 我们在主函数中调用了函数 classifier_images
Classify images returns the result_dic dictionary with
classifier_images 会返回字典 result_dic
the image file name as the key and a list as
其中 字典键为图像文件名
its value where these lists contain the pet image labels,
值为列表 列表中包含了宠物图像标签、
the classifier labels, and whether or not the labels match.
分类器标签以及两种标签的匹配结果
Classify images inputs arguments in_org.dir,
classify_images 要输入的参数有 in_arg.dir
the command line argument for the pet images folder, answers_dic,
即指明 pet_images 文件夹路径的命令行参数
the dictionary with the image file names
字典 answers_dic 该字典以图像文件名为键
as the keys and the pet image labels as the values,
以宠物图像标签为值
and in_org.arch, the command line argument for the CNN model architecture.
in_arg.arch 即 CNN 模型结构的命令行参数
We use this code here as our temporary code to check that our code is working properly.
用这里的临时代码来检查代码效果
We print our matches first and then are non matches and we'll
依次输出匹配和不匹配结果
visually check those to make sure the code is working properly,
进行观察 确保代码无误
then we also check that our non-matches
我们还要检查
plus our matches total the 40 images that we expect.
不匹配数加匹配数是否等于总图像数 即 40
If we open up our terminal window,
如果我们打开终端窗口
we can see where we ran the program up here,
就可以看到这里运行的程序了
and we have our matches print first,
程序依次输出了匹配数
and then our non-matches and visually they appear to be both correct.
和不匹配数 两者都是正确的
We have a total of 40 images,
我们总共有 40 个图像
35 matches, and five non-matches.
匹配数为 35 不匹配数为 5
So it appears our code is working properly.
可见代码无误